

- + 371 29607351
- filipscalijs@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/filipchaly/
- github.com/FilipsCalijs
- Rīga, Latvia

EDUCATION

Secondary education RIGA SECONDARY SCHOOL No. 13

Sep 2013 - May 2022

Riga State Technical School (RSTS)

Computer science

sep 2022 - present

EXPERTISE

Web Design

Frontend

eCommerce

SEO

Marketing

LANGUAGE

English

Latvian

Russian

FILIPS ČALIJS

CV/RESUME

ABOUT ME

I have extensive programming knowledge, particularly in JavaScript and Python, with experience in web development using HTML, CSS/SASS, React, Django, and Webpack. I am proficient in version control with Git/Github and have experience with WordPress and Shopify platforms.

At MediaRock, I analyze traffic and data usage to optimize web content. I completed digital marketing courses from Google, where I learned about traffic analysis, SEO, and website updates from a marketing perspective. Additionally, I have skills in Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator and experience working with Figma.

WORK EXPERIENCE

O March 2022 – June 2024 Riga, Latvia

SEO & MARKETING SUPPORT | MEDIAROCK

Analyzed and processed website traffic and customer data
Added and optimized website content
Creating semantic core and adding mass to the site
Searching for and purchasing a drop domain and adding dofollow/nofollow links

July 2021 – June 2023| Riga, Latvia

CREATING WEBSITES ON WORDPRESS/SHOPIFY

Understanding of project managers Interaction with the server SEO website promotion Web development Experience with Project Manager

January 2022 – April 2022 Udemy Course

THE COMPLETE JAVASCRIPT COURSE | JS

Advanced JavaScript Level Fundamental React level Basics of Redux, MySQL

AWARDS

35th Latvian Informatics Olympiad - 63th place | Regional, 2022

Latvia Code Week Hackathon 2023

Certificate for very good and excellent grades 2023/2024

INTERESTS

Guitar playing

Design

Programming

Swimming and running